Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University February 26, 2021
308 Research Dr
Durham, NC 27705
danyang@cs.duke.edu
https://danyangzhuo.com

Research Interests

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications (e.g., deep learning, big data analytics, packet processing). My approaches include software architecture design, programming languages, and machine learning.

Education

University of Washington - Seattle

Seattle, Washington Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Dep 2015 - Aug ,

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.
- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois – Urbana Champaign

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Urbana, Illinois Aug 2009 - May 2013

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

Professional Experience

Dules IInirrensitu

| _ | Duke University | | | | |
|---|-----------------|-----------|----|----------|---------|
| • | As sist ant | Professor | of | Computer | Science |

University of California – Berkeley

 $Postdoctoral\ Researcher$

- Advisor: Ion Stoica

Microsoft Research

Contractor (through Populous Group)

Microsoft Research

Research Intern

Google

Software Development Engineering Intern

Amazon

Software Development Engineering Intern

Microsoft

• Software Development Engineering Intern

Durham, North Carolina

Jul 2020 - now

Berkeley, California

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017

Redmond, Washington Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Mountain View, California Sep 2014 - Mar 2015

Seattle, Washington

May 2013 - Sep 2013

Redmond, Washington

May 2012 - Aug 2012

Publications

Conference Papers

- 1. Sitan Chen, Xiaoxiao Li, Zhao Song, Danyang Zhuo. On InstaHide, Phase Retrieval, and Sparse Matrix Factorization. The 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021.
- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, Danyang Zhuo, Thomas Anderson. High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento. The 19th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2021.
 Best Paper Award.
- 3. Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, Danyang Zhuo, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. *Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- 4. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Arvind Krishnamurthy. *Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.
- 5. Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel. The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- 7. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- 8. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 9. Vincent Liu, Danyang Zhuo, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking EXperiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

Workshop Papers

- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- 2. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. Canaries in the Network. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.

- 3. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control*. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 4. Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems*. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

Patents

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Danyang Zhuo, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

Students

Current PhD Students

Jingrong Chen (2020-), Guozhen She (2020-), Xinhao Kong (2021-)

Awards 2021 University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up 2018 Rank 146th in the William Lowell Putnam Mathematical Competition 2012 Invited Talk • Towards Efficient Cloud Systems for Data-Intensive Applications. Feb 2021 • Towards Efficient and Reliable Data Center Systems. - Yale University Apr 2019 Apr 2019 Mar 2019 Mar 2019 Mar 2019 - Microsoft Research Mar 2019 Feb 2019 Feb 2019 • Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network. - Princeton University Jun 2020 Feb 2019

| • Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks. | | | | | | |
|---|------|--|--|--|--|--|
| - ACM SIGCOMM | 2017 | | | | | |
| • RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks. | | | | | | |
| – USENIX NSDI | 2017 | | | | | |
| | | | | | | |
| Teaching | | | | | | |
| • CPS 510: Advanced Operating Systems. (Fall 2020) | | | | | | |
| Service | | | | | | |

Program Committee

• SIGCOMM (2020)